A journey like you’ve never imagined.
The Polar Express is a animation, adventure, family
film directed by Robert Zemeckis.
When a doubting young boy takes an extraordinary train ride to the North Pole, he embarks on a journey of
self-discovery that shows him that the wonder of life never fades for those who believe.
Hero Boy (Adult)/ Father / Conductor / Hobo / Scrooge
/ Santa Claus, played by Tom Hanks.
Sister Sarah / Mother, played by Leslie Zemeckis.
Know-It-All, played by Eddie Deezen.
Hero Girl (voice), played by Nona Gaye.
Billy - Lonely Boy, played by Peter Scolari.
Smokey / Steamer, played by Michael Jeter.
The Polar Express is a 2004 American animated Christmas fantasy adventure film directed by Robert Zemeckis, who co-wrote the
screenplay with William Broyles Jr., based on the 1985 children's book of the same name by Chris Van Allsburg.
The film stars Tom Hanks in multiple roles, along with Daryl
Sabara, Nona Gaye, Jimmy Bennett, and Eddie Deezen.
The film depicts human characters using live action and motion capture computer animation, with
production sequences for the latter taking place from June 2003 to May 2004.
Set on Christmas Eve, it tells the story of a young boy who travels to the
North Pole aboard a magical train guided by its conductor.
The Polar Express premiered at the Chicago International Film Festival on
October 13, 2004, and was theatrically released by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United States on November 10.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and initially grossed $286 million against a
record-breaking $165–170 million budget, which was the highest for an animated feature at the time.
Later re-releases helped propel the film's gross to $318.2 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of faith, holiday, santa claus, nerd, bell.
The tone is lighthearted.